BILL **HRONIS**, PMP

Toronto ONTARIO 416.456.9794

bill.hronis@outlook.com

A certified project management professional with over 10 years' experience managing projects and a passion for learning. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to overcome challenges and motivate teams. Known among staff and colleagues for strong leadership, attention to detail and positive attitude no matter the complexity of the challenge or task to deliver success.

EXPERIENCE

OCTOBER 2018 – OCTOBER 2020

DIRECTOR - PMO, CI INVESTMENTS INC.

Key Accomplishments:

- ✓ Lead a team of 8 Program and Project managers executing initiatives to meet corporate objectives.
- ✓ Collaborated with executive leadership to developed and implemented an automated end-to-end project intake process for all project requests of the organization, providing a single point of truth of project initiatives.
- ✓ Collaborated with upper management to developed and implemented a project governance structure for PMO program and project managers, providing a consistent experience for projects with PMO oversight.
- ✓ Developed a project portfolio review and selection process to evaluate project alignment with corporate strategy and strategic impact helping remove project biases from the project selection and prioritization process.
- ✓ Collaborated with executive leadership and implemented a custom, interactive, immersive project dashboard of all projects within the organization using Microsoft Power BI, effectively communicating daily status updates to executive leadership with the ability to drill down to program and project specific data.

OCTOBER 2013 – OCTOBER 2018

PROGRAM MANAGER - PMO, CI INVESTMENTS INC.

Key Accomplishments:

- ✓ Assumed responsibility of a program two years past due and over \$5 million in sunk cost leading the team to a successful rebuild and launch within six months.
- ✓ Managed first major agile project within the organization showcasing the benefits of agile development leading to widespread adoption of agile methodologies throughout development teams' company wide.

AUGUST 2007 – OCTOBER 2013

MANAGER - PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT/IMPLEMENTATION & GOVERNANCE,

CLINVESTMENTS INC.

Key Accomplishments:

- ✓ Developed, implemented and managed segregated fund products generating billions in sales while working closely with insurance partners to ensure available products continued to meet client needs.
- ✓ Demonstrated success in the development and deployment of training materials, to ensure a comprehensive understanding of new product offerings.
- ✓ Provided creative solutions to product issues and gathered information on customer experiences for future product enhancements.

SKILLS

- Leadership
- Strategic Planning and Alignment
- Problem Resolution
- Empathy
- Adaptability
- Waterfall/Agile Methodologies
- Time Management
- Effective Communications
- Prioritization

- Microsoft Office/Teams
- JIRA/Confluence
- Project Online/Power BI
- HTML5/CSS
- JavaScript ES6+
- Node/Express
- React
- MySQL, MongoDB

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATION

PROJECT MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL, PROJECT MANAGEMENT INSTITUTE | 2022

FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATE, UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO SCHOOL OF CONTINUING STUDIES | 2021

LEADING PROJECTS IN ORGANIZATIONS CERTIFICATE, UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO SCHOOL OF CONTINUING STUDIES | 2014

FOUNDATIONS OF PROJECT MANAGEMENT CERTIFICATE, UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO SCHOOL OF CONTINUING STUDIES | 2013

COACHING AND MOTIVATION SEMINAR, GEORGIAN COLLEGE

MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP DEVELOPMENT/LIFO CERTIFICATE, RYERSON UNIVERSITY

PODIUM PRESENTATION SKILL CERTIFICATE, PODIUM CONSULTING INC.

MARKETING DIPLOMA, CENTENNIAL COLLEGE